Guide to the Robert Matyas papers, 1951-2012
Matyas, Robert papers, 1951-2012
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Matyas papers, 1951-2012.
43-01-3368
Robert M. Matyas
7.6 cubic ft.
Photographs, correspondence, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Slides, photographs, and papers concering Matyas' career in facilities at Cornell, including his work on the Superconducting Super Collider, the Laboratory of Nuclear Studies, the Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory, Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory, and various other campus buildings.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Vice-President for Facilities and Business Operations, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Slides, photographs, and papers concering Matyas' career in facilities at Cornell, including his work on the Superconducting Super Collider, the Laboratory of Nuclear Studies, the Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory, Arecibo, and various other campus buildings.
Also, Arecibo photographs by Dale Corson, photographs of Jason Seley sculptures, photographs of the Uris Library addition, other Arecibo and campus scenes, including glass negatives of the Arts Quad.
Also, "Living units for men, Cornell University," 1951, architecture student project report about dormitories at Cornell, by Robert D. Katz, Robert M. Matyas, John I. Williams, and Carlton S. Young; "Some Things I Remember about the Anabel Taylor Interfaith Chapel at Cornell University," 2012
SUBJECTS
Names:
Matyas, Robert M.; Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University.Laboratory of Nuclear Studies.; Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory (Cornell University)
Subjects:
Superconducting Super Collider.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Campus Maintenance Slides (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell Club Slides (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Custodial Slides (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Arecibo Slides (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Arecibo Slides (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arecibo Slides (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Buildings Slides (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cornell University Real Estate Slides, June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cornell University Beebe Lake Slides (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cornell University Campus Slides (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Views of Cornell Slides (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Our Changing Campus Slides (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Our Changing Campus Slides (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Our Changing Campus Slides, Jan. 30, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Assorted Cornell University Slides (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Washington, DC Property Review Slides (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Assorted Cornell University Slides (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Assorted Cornell University Slides (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Assorted Cornell University Slides (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Assorted Cornell University Slides (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Isle of Shoals Slides, July 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Isle of Shoals Slides (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Statler West Slides, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Energy Slide Presentation (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Performing Arts Center at SUNY Purchase Campus Slides (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Uris Library Addition Slides (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Potential Projects Slides (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Assorted CU Slides (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Arecibo Slides (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Custodial Slides (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Critical Maintenance Program Slides (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Uris Hall Construction Slides (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cornell University Dorm Damage Slides (Box 2, Folder 4)
- MS & O, CHP, and CWP Slides (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cornell University Construction Slides (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Cornell University Heating Plant Aerial Photos (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Cornell University Aerial Photos (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Uris Library Addition Photos, Mar. 25, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Arecibo, Miscellaneous Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Wilson Synchrotron Photos (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos, Sapsucker Woods, Ithaca College (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Arecibo (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Assorted Cornell University Photos (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Cornell University Beebe Lake Photos (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Cornell University Construction, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Wilson Synchrotron Photos (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous Photos (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Arecibo Photos, Sept. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Arecibo Photos, A Time of Wonder: The Arecibo Telescope 1974 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Photographs and Negatives (Box 3)
  Harry Burgess, Wisconsin Trip, Tunnel, Isle of Shoals (1980), Commencement (1981), Manchester, NH (1981), Cape Cod (1981), Performing Arts Center, Observatory, Bill Hamilton, Arecibo Main Cable Inspection, Cornell Club in NYC, Toronto, Cornell University Medical College, Cornell University Heating Plant, Ithaca Gun, Cornell University Football, World Trade Center (Feb. 1987), New York City, California (1987), Chicago, Atlanta (Feb. 1987), Baker Laboratory, Washington, DC, Uris Library Addition, Cornell University Construction, Mining, Massachusetts Avenue House in Washington, DC, Geology Building Construction, Sab Micron Lab, Day Hall, VCAT, Sibley Hall, Mrs. Robert Purcell, St. Lawrence River, Pew Quad Dedication (1980), Cornell University Career Center, Statler West, Risley Hall, East Avenue, Nick Noyes, Indianapolis, Boston, assorted Cornell University views, assorted Arecibo views, and miscellaneous shots as well as slides of the following: New York City, Cornell University Construction, Performing Arts Center, Statler, Cornell University Medical College, Olin Library Construction, Uris Library, assorted Cornell University views, assorted Arecibo views, and assorted Ithaca views
- Quill & Dagger Alumni Association (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Facility Budget (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Our Changing Campus (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Nuclear Studies at Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Nuclear Studies at Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Cornell University Medical College: Lasdon Biomedical Research Center (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence with F.R. Newman (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Newspaper Articles regarding the Wilson Synchrotron (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Cornell University Medical College: Miscellany (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Monetary Gifts to Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Building Plans for Cornell Club in New York City (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Publications regarding the Wilson Synchrotron (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Construction, Buildings, and Properties at Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Cornell Synchrotron Laboratory: Construction Specification for Laboratory Building Construction, Nov. 15, 1965 (Box 4)
- Fermilab 1987: Annual Report of the Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory (Box 4)
- AD Meeting (Box 4)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Arecibo Photos (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Central Avenue Redevelopment: Cornell University (Box 5)
- Photos-Geological Sciences Facility, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Photos-Geological Sciences Facility, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Photos-Geological Sciences Facility, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Photos-Geological Sciences Facility, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Photos-Geological Sciences Facility, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Constructionm Department (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Photos-Various Campus Buildings, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Various Campus Photos (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Facts About Cornell (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Day Hall Space Issues (I), 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Day Hall Space Issues (II), 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Day Hall Space Issues (III), 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Transcript of Talk Given by Steven Muller, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Book: Status of Old Country Club Land in Cayuga Heights (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Book: Campus Development Guidelines, Cornell University, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Framed photograph: Uris Library addition interior, Cornell University (Box 7)
- Framed photograph: Uris Library exterior, Cornell University (Box 7)
- Framed photograph: Johnson Museum exterior after dark, Cornell University (Box 7)
- Framed photograph: Jason Seley sculpture, Cornell University (Box 8)
- Framed photograph: Wilson Synchrotron exterior, Cornell University (Box 8)
- Photograph: Arecibo (Box 9)
- Framed photograph: Arecibo nuts and bolts assembly (Box 9)
- Framed photograph: Pillar at Arecibo (Box 9)
- Framed photograph: Arecibo girder assembly (Box 9)
- Framed photograph: Arecibo (Box 9)
- Framed photograph: Jason Seley sculpture of nude man in Johnson Museum foyer, Cornell University (Box 9)
- Framed photograph: Jason Seley sculpture of man astride horse, Cornell University (Box 9)
- Dedications (Box 10, Folder 1)
- CU construction progress photos (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Snee Hall (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Living Units for Men (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Newman Lab (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Appointment letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Log Book, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Beebe Lake and surrounding area (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous photos and slides of campus (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Photograph: Jason Seley sculpture of Hercules, Johnson Museum, Cornell University (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Photograph: Boyce McDaniel (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Photograph: New York City (?) (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Photograph: Wilson Nuclear Laboratory (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Photograph: Arecibo (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Living Units for Men (2 copies), 1951 (Box 12)
- Photographs: Arecibo (Box 12)
- Presentation: "Supplementary Facilities for the Laboatory of Nuclear Studies, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY (Loose pages on board), 1952 (Box 12)
- Photographs: Wilson Nuclear Laboratory (Box 12)
- Photographs: Wilson Nuclear Laboratory (loose photographs) (Box 12)
- Glass negatives of Arts Quad, n.d. (Box 13)
- Photographs: Aerial photos of various Cornell buildings (Box 13)
- Photographs: Arecibo (Box 13)
- Slides of Arecibo (Box 13)
- "Some Things I Remember about the Anabel Taylor Interfaith Chapel at Cornell University" by Robert M. Matyas, 2012 (Box 13)
- Drawings of Performing Arts Center, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Synchrotron, interior construction, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Ruth Uris Garden dedication group photo (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Power plant, Uris Library and McGraw Tower (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Slides: campus scenes, some sporting events and Johnson Museum, ca. 1980's (Box 14, Folder 5)
- 10 loose photos of campus buildings mounted on foam board, n.d. (Box 14)